[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Risk factors for nutritional deficiency do not include one of the following",
    "options": [
      "High socio-economic status",
      "Total parenteral nutrition",
      "Genetic disease",
      "Specific drug therapies",
      "Chronic alcoholism"
    ],
    "answer": ["High socio-economic status"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'High socio-economic status.' \nRisk factors for nutritional deficiency includes \n1. Poverty\n2. Infections\n3. Acute and chronic illnesses\n4. Chronic alcoholism\n5. Ignorance and failure of diet supplementation\n6. Self-imposed dietary restriction\n7. Gastrointestinal diseases and malabsorption syndromes\n8. Genetic diseases\n9. Specific drug therapies (which block uptake or utilization of particular nutrients)\n10. Total parenteral nutrition",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Enviromental and Nutritional Diseases"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which of the following is correct about protein-energy malnutrition?",
    "options": [
      "The body mass index(BMI) is less than 18.5kg/m2",
      "The visceral protein compartment is more severely affected in marasmus",
      "The visceral protein compartment is less severely affected in kwashiorkor",
      "The somatic protein compartment is less severely affected in kwashoirkor",
      "The somatic protein compartment is more severely affected in kwashiorkor"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "The somatic protein compartment is less severely affected in kwashoirkor"
    ],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'The somatic protein compartment is less severely affected in kwashiorkor.' \n\n Malnutrition is defined by a BMI less than 16 kg/m2: (normal range 18.5 to 25 kg/m2). More practicaiiy, a child weighing less than 80% of normal is considered malnourished. \n\nHowever, weight loss may be masked by generalized oedema. Other helpful parameters in evaluating a patient for malnutrition include the \n1. assessment of fat stores (thickness of skin folds),\n2. muscle mass (reduced mid-arm circumference).\n3. and serum proteins (albumin and transferrin) estimation.\n\nFunctionally there are two protein compartments regulated differently in the body:\n1. the somatic compartment (proteins in skeletal muscle) \n2. and the visceral compartment (protein stores mainly in the liver).\n The somatic compartment is more severely affected in marasmus, whereas the visceral compartment is more severely affected in kwashiorkor.\n\nA child is said to be marasmic when weight falls below 60% of that expected for age, sex and height. \n In marasmus \n 1. The extremities are thin and the head appears disproportionately large compared to the body. \n2. The visceral protein compartment which is presumably more critical for survival is much less affected, as reflected in normal or near-normal serum albumin levels.\n3. Low levels of leptin stimulate the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis resulting in increased cortisol, and promoting lipolysis. \nThere is also\n4.  anaemia,\n5. manifestations of vitamin and micronutrient deficiencies, \n6. and defects in immunity (especially T cell mediated immunity), which predispose to infections which themselves impose additional nutritional demands. \n\n Kwashiorkor occurs when the protein deficiency is relatively more severe than the total calorie depletion.\nThe marked protein deprivation results in \n1. severe depletion of the visceral protein compartment, and the resultant hypoalbuminaemia results in dependent or generalized oedema. \n2. Weight loss is masked by oedema and there is relative sparing of skeletal muscle mass and subcutaneous fat. \n3. kwashoirkor patients have characteristic skin lesions, with alternating zones of hyperpigmentation, areas of desquamation, and hypopigmentation, giving a 'flaky paint' appearance. \n4. There may be overall loss of hair colour or alternating bands of darker and paler hair\n5. There is enlarged, fatty liver owing to shortfalls in the synthesis of the carrier protein component of lipoproteins, apathy, listlessness and loss of appetite.\n6 There is also vitamin deficiencies, immune defects, and secondary infections.\n\n Secondary PEM often develops in chronically ill, elderly, and bedridden patients, and the most obvious signs include: \n1. depletion of subcutaneous fat in the arms, chest wall, shoulders, or metacarpal regions; \n2. wasting of the quadriceps femoris and deltoid muscles; and \n3. ankle or sacral edema.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Protein energy malnutrition, obesity and diseases"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Which of the following statement is correct about the pathogenesis of obesity?",
    "options": [
      "There are complex neuro-humoral mechanisms involving the stimulation centers located in the thalamus",
      "POMC/CART neurons are first order neurons while NPY/AgRP are second order neurons",
      "POMC/CART neurons are orexigenic while NPY/AgRP neurons are  anorexigenic",
      "Adiponectin levels are higher in the lean than in the obese",
      "Ghrelin works most likely by binding to POMC/CART neurons"
    ],
    "answer": ["Adiponectin levels are higher in the lean than in the obese"],
    "explanation": "The pathogenesis of obesity is very complex and as yet incompletely understood. \n\n There are certain complex neuro-humoral mechanisms controlling appetite and satiety and these are influenced by genetic, nutritional, environmental and psychologic signals, triggering a metabolic response by stimulation of centres located in the hypothalamus. Obesity is thus multifactorial in its origin and mechanisms, \n\nThe neuro-humoral mechanisms regulating energy balance include following components: \n1. The peripheral or afferent system generates signals from various sites. Its main components are \na. leptin and adiponectin produced by fat cells,\nb. ghrelin from the stomach,\nc. peptide YY (PYY) from the ileum and colon and \nd. insulin from the pancreas \n2. The arcuate nucleus in the hypothalamus processes and integrates neurohumoral peripheral signals and generates efferent signals. It contains two subsets of first-order neurons: \na. POMC (pro-opiomelanocortin) and CART (cocaine and amphetamine regulated transcripts) neurons. and \nb. neurons containing NPY (neuropeptide Y) and AgRP (agouti-related peptide).\n Note POMC/CART and NPY/ArRp are first order neurons and these first order neurons communicate with second order. \n3. The efferent system that carries the signals generated in the second order neurons of the hypothalamus to control food intake and energy expenditure. The hypothalamic system communicates with forebrain and midbrain centers that control the autonomic system \n\nPOMC/CART neurons enhance energy expenditure and weight loss (anorexigenic) while NPY/AgRP neurons promote food intake (orexigenic effect).\n\n Ghrelin increases caloric intake while decreasing energy utilization, most likely by binding to NPY/AgRP neurons to increase food intake \n\n Mainly produced by adipocytes, adiponectin levels are usually very high in the blood. but are lower in the obese than in the lean. When injected in mice, they stimulate fatty acid oxidation in muscle, decreasing overall fat mass. The effects are similar in humans: this 'fat-burning molecule' and 'guardian angel against obesity' directs fatty acids to muscle for their oxidation. inactivating acetyl coenzyme A carboxylase, a key enzyme required for fatty acid synthesis. It decreases the influx of fatty acids to the liver and the total hepatic triglyceride content, and also decreases the glucose production in the liver, causing an increase in insulin sensitivity and a protection against the metabolic syndrome.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Protein energy malnutrition, obesity and diseases"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "A 25 year old lady driving beyond the speed limit is ordered by a police officer to pull over and alight from her car. She is noticed to be drowsy. An alcohol breath test is immediately administered. Which is the most likely finding?",
    "options": ["105 mg/dL", "205mg/dL", "305mg/dl", "405mg/dL", "505mg/dL"],
    "answer": ["205mg/dL"],
    "explanation": "An Alcohol concentration of <b>80mg/dl</b> in the blood constitutes the legal definition of drunk driving in the united states. \n\bDrowsiness occurs at <b>200mg/dl</b> \n\bStupor at <b>300mg/dl</b> \n\band coma with possible respiratory arrest at higher levels",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "A 25 year old lady said to be watching her weight collapses and is rushed to the Emergency Room. On examination, she is unconscious and serverely dehydrated. Her serum electrolytes are found to be deranged and her blood count shows anaemia and lymphopenia. Which of the following features of the condition is she most likely suffers from is most diagnostic?",
    "options": [
      "Cardiac arrhythmia",
      "Bradycardia",
      "Constipation",
      "Amenorrhea",
      "Dry and scaly skin"
    ],
    "answer": ["Amenorrhea"],
    "explanation": "The clinical findings in anorexia nervosa are generally as seen in severe Protein-Energy Malnutritions. \n\nIn addition. effects on the endocrine system are obvious such as amenorrhea, from decreased secretion of luteinizing hormone and follicle-stimulating hormone secondary to decreased secretion of gonadotropin-releasing hormone. Amenorrhoea is so common in anorexia nervosa that its presence is a diagnostic feature for the disorder.\n\n Other common findings \n1. relate to decreased thyroid hormone release, and include \na. cold intolerance,\nb. bradycardia,\nc. constipation, and  \nd. changes in the skin and hair. \n2. Dehydration and electrolyte abnormalities are frequent. The skin becomes dry and scaly.\n3. Bone density is decreased, possibly from low estrogen levels, mimicking post- menopausal osteoporosis. \n4. Anemia, lymphopenia, and hypoalbuminemia may be present. \n5. Anorexia nervosa (and also bulimia) can be complicated by hypokalaemia resulting in an increased susceptibility to cardiac arrhythmias and sudden death.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "One of the following is always a malignant tumour",
    "options": [
      "Hepatoma",
      "Lipoblastoma",
      "Mesothelioma",
      "Ameloblastoma",
      "Insulinoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Hepatoma"],
    "explanation": "Among the options provided, hepatoma is always considered a malignant tumor. Hepatoma, also known as hepatocellular carcinoma, arises from liver cells and is associated with a high malignancy potential. It is crucial to recognize the malignant nature of hepatoma, as early detection and intervention are essential for effective treatment and improved outcomes.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Features of anaplasia include all except",
    "options": [
      "Nucleomegaly",
      "Cytomegaly",
      "Nucleolomegaly",
      "Loss of polarity",
      "Increased mitoses"
    ],
    "answer": ["Cytomegaly"],
    "explanation": "Anaplasia refers to the lack of differentiation and loss of the specialized characteristics of cells.\n Anaplastic cells often display the following morphologic features:\n1. Pleomorphism (i.e., variation in size and shape) \n2. Nuclear abnormalities, consisting of extreme hyperchromatism (dark-staining), variation in nuclear size and shape, or unusually prominent single or multiple nucleoli. Enlargement of nuclei may result in an increasednuclear-to-cytoplasmic ratio that approaches 1 :1 insteadof the normal 1: 4 or 1 : 6. Nucleoli may attain astounding sizes, sometimes approaching the diameter ofnormal lymphocytes.\n3. Tumor giant cells may be formed. These are considerablylarger than neighboring cells and may possess eitherone enormous nucleus or several nuclei. \n4. Atypical mitoses, which may be numerous. Anarchic multiple spindles may produce tripolar or quadripolar mitotic figures \n5. Loss of polarity, such that anaplastic cells lack recognizable patterns of orientation to one another. Such cells may grow in sheets, with total loss of communal",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Neoplasia, Characteristics of Benign and malignant neoplasms"],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Which of the following is most unlikely to metastasize?",
    "options": [
      "Renal cell carcinoma",
      "Papillary thyroid carcinoma",
      "Non-Hodgkin lymphoma",
      "Brain stem glioma",
      "Osteosarcoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Brain stem glioma"],
    "explanation": "All malignanat tumors metasize frequently except \n\b1. Gliomas (malignant CNS tumors) and \n\b2. Basal cell carcinoma(skin). \n\bBrain tumors, particularly gliomas located in the brain stem, often have limited potential for metastasis outside the central nervous system. Unlike other listed cancers, which can spread to distant organs, brain stem gliomas primarily affect the central nervous system, making metastasis uncommon. However, it's crucial to note that brain stem gliomas can be locally aggressive and pose significant challenges in terms of treatment and prognosis.",

    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Neoplasia, Characteristics of Benign and malignant neoplasms"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "One of the following is not an autosomal recessive inherited cancer syndrome",
    "options": [
      "Bloom syndrome",
      "Li Fraumeni syndrome",
      "Fanconi anaemia",
      "Xerodema pigmentosum",
      "Ataxia telagiectasia"
    ],
    "answer": ["Li Fraumeni syndrome"],
    "explanation": "Li Fraumeni syndrome is not an autosomal recessive inherited cancer syndrome. It is an autosomal dominant inherited syndrome characterized by an increased risk of various cancers at a young age. In contrast, the other syndromes listed are autosomal recessive, meaning that both copies of the gene must be mutated for the syndrome to manifest. Li Fraumeni syndrome is associated with mutations in the TP53 tumor suppressor gene and is known for a high predisposition to a wide range of cancers in affected individuals and their families.",

    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "One of the following is not a feature of familial clustering of cancers",
    "options": [
      "Occur at an early age",
      "Affect 2-3 family members",
      "Are associated with bilateralism",
      "Are associated with tumours in the same subject",
      "Are autosomal dominant inherited"
    ],
    "answer": ["Are autosomal dominant inherited"],
    "explanation": "Familial clustering of cancers is often associated with shared genetic susceptibility, but it is not necessarily linked to autosomal dominant inheritance. While some cancer predisposition syndromes are inherited in an autosomal dominant manner, the familial clustering of cancers can also result from shared environmental factors or a combination of genetic and environmental influences. Therefore, the presence of familial clustering does not always imply autosomal dominant inheritance, as multiple factors can contribute to the observed pattern of cancer occurrence within a family.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Neoplasia, Characteristics of Benign and malignant neoplasms"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "The assessment of tumor monoclonality is demostrable by the following save",
    "options": [
      "Analysis of T cell receptor gene rearrangement",
      "Cytogenetic studies",
      "Phosphoglycerate kinase",
      "Analysis of methylation patterns adjacent to the human oestrogen receptor gene",
      "Iduronate-2-sulfatase"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Analysis of methylation patterns adjacent to the human oestrogen receptor gene"
    ],
    "explanation": "The assessment of tumor monoclonality is demonstrable by analyzing methylation patterns adjacent to the human estrogen receptor gene. Clonality studies, including the analysis of DNA methylation patterns, can help determine whether a tumor arises from a single cell (monoclonal) or multiple cells (polyclonal). Methylation analysis provides insights into the epigenetic changes associated with monoclonal expansion. Other listed options, such as T cell receptor gene rearrangement and cytogenetic studies, are also methods used to assess clonality in specific contexts, but the analysis of methylation patterns adjacent to the human estrogen receptor gene is a commonly employed technique.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Regarding the molecular basis of carcinogenesis, four major classes of genes are the targets of genetic damage: Which statement is incorrect?",
    "options": [
      "Apoptotic genes are autosomal dominant",
      "Apoptotic genes are autosomal recessive",
      "Proto-oncogens are autosomal dominant",
      "DNA repair genes are autosomal dominant",
      "Tumour suppressor genes are autosomal recessive"
    ],
    "answer": ["DNA repair genes are autosomal dominant"],
    "explanation": "The incorrect statement is 'DNA repair genes are autosomal dominant.' In reality, DNA repair genes are often autosomal recessive. These genes play a crucial role in maintaining genomic stability by repairing DNA damage. Mutations in DNA repair genes can lead to impaired DNA repair mechanisms, increasing the risk of accumulating genetic damage and promoting carcinogenesis. Autosomal recessive inheritance means that both copies of the gene must be mutated for the phenotype (defective DNA repair) to manifest.",

    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Neoplasia, Characteristics of Benign and malignant neoplasms"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "The INK4/ARF family of cell cycle inhibitors includes all except",
    "options": ["p15", "p16", "p18", "p19", "p21"],
    "answer": ["p21"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'p21.' The INK4/ARF family of cell cycle inhibitors includes p15, p16, p18, and p19. These proteins play a crucial role in regulating the cell cycle by inhibiting cyclin-dependent kinases (CDKs). However, p21 is not part of the INK4/ARF family; it belongs to a different family of cell cycle inhibitors known as the Cip/Kip family. Like the INK4/ARF proteins, p21 also regulates CDKs and contributes to cell cycle control.",

    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Neoplasia, Characteristics of Benign and malignant neoplasms"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "One statement below is correct concerning retinoblastoma and the Rb gene",
    "options": [
      "The Rb gene is located on Ch13p14",
      "Most casses of retinoblstoma are familial",
      "The E6 protein of high-risk human papilloma virus strains inactivates Rb",
      "Matuartion/differentiation of tumour cells rarely occurs",
      "Retinoblastoma affects 1 in 20,000 infants/children"
    ],
    "answer": ["Retinoblastoma affects 1 in 20,000 infants/children"],
    "explanation": "The correct statement is 'Retinoblastoma affects 1 in 20,000 infants/children.' Retinoblastoma is a rare childhood cancer of the eye that typically occurs in early childhood. The Rb gene, associated with retinoblastoma, is located on chromosome 13q14. While some cases of retinoblastoma are familial due to inherited mutations in the Rb gene, most cases are sporadic. The E6 protein of high-risk human papillomavirus strains is associated with inactivating the p53 tumor suppressor protein, not the Rb gene.",

    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Which of the following is a caretaker gene?",
    "options": ["Tp53", "MDM2", "Cyclin D1", "p16", "GADD 45"],
    "answer": ["GADD 45"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'GADD 45.' Caretaker genes are involved in maintaining genomic stability and integrity. GADD 45 (Growth Arrest and DNA Damage-inducible 45) is one such gene that plays a role in the cellular response to DNA damage. It participates in cell cycle arrest and DNA repair processes, contributing to the maintenance of genomic stability. The other listed genes, such as Tp53 (p53), MDM2, Cyclin D1, and p16, are associated with various aspects of cell cycle regulation and tumor suppression.",

    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Neoplasia, Characteristics of Benign and malignant neoplasms"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Which of the following is incorrect about the steps involved in chemical carcinogenesis?",
    "options": [
      "Initiation causes permanent DNA damage",
      "Promoters cause irreversible DNA damage",
      "Initiation alone is not sufficient for tumorigenesis",
      "Promoters cause tumours in initiated cells despite delayed application",
      "Promoters cannot cause tumours when applied before initiators"
    ],
    "answer": ["Promoters cause irreversible DNA damage"],
    "explanation": "The incorrect statement is 'Promoters cause irreversible DNA damage.' In chemical carcinogenesis, initiation involves the induction of permanent DNA damage, often through mutagenic agents. However, promoters are substances that contribute to the progression of initiated cells toward a malignant phenotype, but they do not cause irreversible DNA damage. Promoters act by enhancing the growth and survival of initiated cells. The other statements correctly describe key aspects of chemical carcinogenesis, including the roles of initiation and promotion.",

    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Neoplasia, Characteristics of Benign and malignant neoplasms"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "All are procarcinogens except",
    "options": [
      "Cyclophosphamide",
      "Aflatoxin",
      "Benzo(a)pyrene",
      "Vinyl chloride",
      "Asbestos"
    ],
    "answer": ["Cyclophosphamide"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Cyclophosphamide.' Procarcinogens are substances that can be metabolically converted into active carcinogens. Cyclophosphamide, on the other hand, is an example of a chemotherapeutic agent used to treat cancer, and it is not a procarcinogen. The other listed substances, including aflatoxin, benzo(a)pyrene, vinyl chloride, and asbestos, have procarcinogenic properties, meaning that they can undergo metabolic activation to become carcinogenic.",

    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Neoplasia, Characteristics of Benign and malignant neoplasms"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "A 40 year old male cancer patient is found to have synchronous primary malignant tumours in the breast, brain and adrenals. Molecular genetic analysis will most likely reveal a mutation in which gene?",
    "options": ["Tp53", "RB", "RAS", "MyC", "PTEN"],
    "answer": ["Tp53"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Tp53.' Synchronous primary malignant tumors in different organs suggest a genetic predisposition to cancer. Tp53 (p53) is a tumor suppressor gene that plays a crucial role in preventing the development of cancer. Mutations in the TP53 gene are commonly associated with Li-Fraumeni syndrome, which predisposes individuals to a wide spectrum of cancers, including breast cancer, brain tumors, and adrenal tumors. Molecular genetic analysis in this case is likely to reveal a mutation in the TP53 gene.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Neoplasia, Characteristics of Benign and malignant neoplasms"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "A 55 year old woman with a family history of colorectal cancer has just been diagnosed herself with the same after an endoscopic procedure that revealed multiple polyps. Which of the following genes is least likely to have been involved in this carcinogenesis?",
    "options": ["APC", "RAS", "MSH-2", "p53", "SMAD4"],
    "answer": ["MSH-2"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'MSH-2.' The scenario described suggests a hereditary colorectal cancer syndrome, and multiple polyps are a characteristic feature of familial adenomatous polyposis (FAP). MSH-2 is a mismatch repair gene associated with hereditary nonpolyposis colorectal cancer (HNPCC), also known as Lynch syndrome. While Lynch syndrome can lead to colorectal cancer, it is not typically characterized by the presence of multiple polyps. APC, the gene mutated in FAP, is more likely to be involved in this scenario.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Which of the following chemical carcinogens is incorrectly matched with the associated neoplasm?",
    "options": [
      "Nickel and chromium-lung cancer",
      "Arsenic-skin cancer",
      "Asbestos-gastric cancer",
      "β-naphthlamine-liver cancer",
      "Aflatoxin B1-hepatoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["β-naphthlamine-liver cancer"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'β-naphthylamine-liver cancer.' Chemical carcinogens can be associated with specific neoplasms. However, β-naphthylamine is more commonly associated with bladder cancer, not liver cancer. Exposure to β-naphthylamine is a known risk factor for bladder cancer, particularly in certain occupational settings. The other pairings correctly match chemical carcinogens with their associated neoplasms.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Neoplasia, Characteristics of Benign and malignant neoplasms"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Common benign childhood tumors include",
    "options": [
      "Dysgerminoma",
      "Dermoid cyst",
      "Hepatoblastoma",
      "Ewing's sarcoma",
      "Rhabdosarcoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Dermoid cyst"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Dermoid cyst.' Dermoid cysts are common benign tumors that can occur in childhood. These cysts are typically composed of tissues derived from multiple germ cell layers and can contain elements such as hair, sebaceous material, and teeth. Dermoid cysts are often found in the ovaries but can also occur in other locations. The other options represent malignant tumors or tumors that are less commonly benign in childhood.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": ["Neoplasia, Characteristics of Benign and malignant neoplasms"],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "A 4 month old infant was found dead in bed while asleep. Examination of death scene and autopsy were not contributory. Which of the following statemants is correct about this case",
    "options": [
      "It is known as court death",
      "Cause is usually known",
      "It is the commonest cause of death in infants",
      "Immaturity of the lungs has been implicated",
      "The prone sleeping position increases the risk"
    ],
    "answer": ["The prone sleeping position increases the risk"],
    "explanation": "The correct statement is 'The prone sleeping position increases the risk.' Sudden infant death syndrome (SIDS), also known as cot death, is the sudden and unexplained death of an otherwise healthy infant, often during sleep. The prone (face-down) sleeping position has been identified as a risk factor for SIDS. While the exact cause of SIDS is not always known, certain sleep practices, including placing infants on their backs to sleep, have been recommended to reduce the risk of SIDS.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "A 22 month old child presented with a left sided large abdominal mass that has crossed the mid line. Histology showed a small round blue tumour. Genetic studies showed abnormalities with WT1 and PAX 6 genes. Which of the comments is true of the most probable diagnosis?",
    "options": [
      "About 70% are bilateral",
      "It can undergo spontaneous remission",
      "Rosettes are usually formed by the turmour cells",
      "2 year survival rate may be as high as 90%",
      "patients may present with projectile vomiting"
    ],
    "answer": ["2 year survival rate may be as high as 90%"],
    "explanation": "The correct statement is '2-year survival rate may be as high as 90%.'\n\n The clinical presentation described is consistent with a Wilms tumor, Most common renal tumor of childhood and 4th most common pediatric malignancy in the US.\n\n Wilms tumors often present as large abdominal masses (Unilateral or bilateral) which if unilateral may extend across the midline, \n\n Hematuria, abdominal pain, intestinal obstruction, Hypertention may be present at 1st presentation/diagnosis \n\nand genetic abnormalities, including mutations in WT1 and PAX 6 genes in WAGR syndrome, WT1 in Denys-Drash syndrome and WT-2 in Beeckwith-wiedemann syndrome, are associated with their development. \n\n Prognosis is usually very good with a combination of nephrectomy and chemotherapy. \n\n2 years survival rates are as high as 90% and this usually implies a cure. Along with increased survival is also the increased incidence of second primary tumour mainly due to the long term side effect of chemotherapy",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "A 2 year old girl presented to the paediatrician with a 3 month history of abdominal mass and ascites. Ascitic fluid cytology reveled a malignant smear. What is the possible diagnosis?",
    "options": [
      "Retinoblastoma",
      "Fibroma",
      "Medulloblastoma",
      "Pheochromocytoma",
      "Neuroblastoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Neuroblastoma"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Neuroblastoma.' Neuroblastoma is a malignant tumor that arises from neural crest cells. It is the second most common malignancy of childhood (650 cases / year in USA) \n\n NEUROBLASTIC TUMOURS includes tumours of the sympathetic ganglia and the adrenal medulla that are derived from the primordial neural crest cells. These tumours have the ability to spontaneously or therapy-induced undergo differentiation into mature elements and also to undergo spontaneous remission.(Others include; Melanoma, Choriocarcinoma, adenocarcinomas). It commonly presents with an abdominal mass, ascites, and, in some cases, elevated catecholamine levels. The tumor is most frequently seen in young children, and malignant cells can be identified in ascitic fluid cytology. Neuroblastoma is one of the most common solid tumors in childhood.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "The possible morphological features of a baby that died of fetal hydrops",
    "options": [
      "Oedema is always generalised",
      "Presence of dysmorphic features",
      "The cause is always of immune origin",
      "Central cyanosis",
      "Cardiomegaly"
    ],
    "answer": ["Presence of dysmorphic features"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Presence of dysmorphic features.' Fetal hydrops is a condition characterized by abnormal accumulation of fluid in fetal compartments. It can result from various causes, including immune and non-immune factors. The presence of dysmorphic features suggests an underlying genetic or structural abnormality. Fetal hydrops is associated with poor outcomes and may involve fluid accumulation in multiple spaces, leading to generalized edema.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "A 39 year old Managing Director of a commercial bank gave birth to a 4.2kg baby at term. Which of the following is a predisposing factor",
    "options": [
      "Maternal DM",
      "Cigarette smoking",
      "Social class V1",
      "Hypertension",
      "Fetal alcholol syndrome"
    ],
    "answer": ["Maternal DM"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Maternal DM' (Diabetes Mellitus). Diabetes in pregnancy, especially uncontrolled diabetes, can lead to fetal macrosomia (large birth weight). Infants born to mothers with diabetes may experience excessive growth due to increased glucose crossing the placenta. This can result in a higher risk of complications during labor and delivery, as well as potential issues for the newborn, such as birth injuries.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "A 25 year old school dropout gave birth to a 2.3kg baby at term. What are the possible implicating factors",
    "options": [
      "Maternal DM",
      "Narcotic abuse",
      "Under age",
      "Over nutrition",
      "Fragile-X syndrome"
    ],
    "answer": ["Narcotic abuse"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Narcotic abuse.' Narcotic (opioid) abuse during pregnancy can have detrimental effects on the developing fetus. It is associated with low birth weight, prematurity, and an increased risk of neonatal abstinence syndrome (NAS). NAS occurs when a newborn experiences withdrawal symptoms due to exposure to addictive substances during pregnancy. It is crucial to identify and address substance abuse issues in pregnant individuals to optimize outcomes for both the mother and the baby.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "About neonatal respiratory distress syndrome",
    "options": [
      "The characteristic X-ray finding is that of patchy opacities",
      "Systemic hypertension is a risk factor",
      "More females are affected",
      "There is deficiency of pulmonary surfactant",
      "Normal labour increases the risk"
    ],
    "answer": ["There is deficiency of pulmonary surfactant"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'There is a deficiency of pulmonary surfactant.' Neonatal respiratory distress syndrome (NRDS) is a condition primarily affecting premature infants. It results from a deficiency of pulmonary surfactant, a substance that helps keep the air sacs in the lungs open. The lack of surfactant leads to increased surface tension, making it difficult for the infant to breathe. NRDS is characterized by respiratory distress, tachypnea, and chest retractions. Treatment may involve surfactant replacement therapy.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "About 'SEQUENCES'",
    "options": [
      "It is a single gene disorder",
      "It is a constellation of congenital abnormalities",
      "It is absence of primordial structures",
      "It is a pattern of cascade abnormalities",
      "Down's syndrome is an example"
    ],
    "answer": ["It is a pattern of cascade abnormalities"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'It is a pattern of cascade abnormalities.' In medical terms, 'sequences' refer to a pattern of anomalies resulting from a single primary anomaly. Unlike syndromes, which involve a constellation of abnormalities often caused by multiple factors, sequences are typically a cascade of events initiated by a primary anomaly. Down's syndrome, on the other hand, is an example of a chromosomal disorder caused by the presence of an extra chromosome 21 (trisomy 21), and it is not specifically a 'sequence.'",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "Which of the following genes has been implicated for congenital defects",
    "options": ["p53 gene", "Rb gene", "PAX gene", "Bcl-2 gene", "APC gene"],
    "answer": ["PAX gene"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'PAX gene.' PAX (Paired Box) genes are a family of transcription factors that play a crucial role in embryonic development. Mutations in PAX genes have been implicated in various congenital defects, affecting the development of organs and tissues. These defects can lead to a wide range of abnormalities, including those in the central nervous system, eyes, and other structures. Understanding the role of PAX genes is essential in the study of congenital malformations.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "Reduced plasma osmotic pressure can be caused by",
    "options": [
      "Constrictive pericardis",
      "Venous thrombosis",
      "Liver cirrhosis",
      "Congestive cardiac failure",
      "Increase tubular reabsorption of sodium"
    ],
    "answer": ["Liver cirrhosis"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Liver cirrhosis.' Liver cirrhosis can lead to reduced plasma osmotic pressure due to impaired synthesis of plasma proteins, including albumin, by the damaged liver. Albumin plays a crucial role in maintaining osmotic pressure. In liver cirrhosis, there is a decrease in the production of albumin, contributing to hypoalbuminemia and reduced osmotic pressure. This can result in fluid accumulation in the extravascular space, leading to conditions such as ascites.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Which of the following is a true statement?",
    "options": [
      "Congestion is a passive process with atresia of the vessels and stasis",
      "In hyperaemia the tissue has blue-red coloration",
      "Transudate is protein rich fluid with specific gravity of 1.012",
      "Heavy presence of heart failure cells in acute pulmonary congestion",
      "Acute hepatic congestion is characterized by distension of the central vein with or without hepatocyte degeneration"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Acute hepatic congestion is characterized by distension of the central vein with or without hepatocyte degeneration"
    ],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Acute hepatic congestion is characterized by distension of the central vein with or without hepatocyte degeneration.' In acute hepatic congestion, increased blood flow to the liver may lead to distension of the central vein. This can be associated with hepatocyte degeneration. Congestion is a passive process resulting from impaired outflow of blood, while hyperemia refers to active increased blood flow. The presence of heart failure cells is more associated with chronic congestion.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "Which of the following statement is false?",
    "options": [
      "Petechial haemorrhage is small pinpoint haemorrhage on the mucosal surface of skine less than 3mm in size",
      "Purpuras are haemorrhages on the skin or mucosal surface whose size is more than 2cm",
      "Haematoma is focal accumulation of blood",
      "In Ecchymosis, the blood in the mucosal surface is more than 1cm but less than 2cm in size",
      "Thrombus is a solid mass of blood constituents within the blood vessels"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Purpuras are haemorrhages on the skin or mucosal surface whose size is more than 2cm"
    ],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Purpuras are hemorrhages on the skin or mucosal surface whose size is more than 2cm.' Purpuras typically refer to hemorrhages that are smaller than ecchymoses but larger than petechiae. The size of purpuras is generally between 0.3 cm and 1 cm. Petechial hemorrhage is characterized by small pinpoint hemorrhages, while ecchymosis involves larger areas of hemorrhage, usually between 1 cm and 2 cm in size.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "The following can predispose to thrombus formation except",
    "options": [
      "Stasis",
      "turbulence",
      "Atherosclerosis",
      "Hypercoagulability",
      "Deficiency of vitamin C"
    ],
    "answer": ["Deficiency of vitamin C"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Deficiency of vitamin C.' While stasis, turbulence, atherosclerosis, and hypercoagulability are known factors that can predispose to thrombus formation, deficiency of vitamin C is not typically associated with an increased risk of thrombosis. Vitamin C is essential for collagen synthesis and has a role in maintaining blood vessel integrity, but its deficiency is not a recognized independent risk factor for thrombus formation.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "Which of the following is false?",
    "options": [
      "Arterial thrombi are usually occlusive",
      "Arterial thrombi can occur in the cerebral artery",
      "Venous thrombi are almost invariably occlusive",
      "Veinous thromus takes the shape of the vein",
      "Phlebothrombosis commonly affects the vein of the upper extremities"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Phlebothrombosis commonly affects the vein of the upper extremities"
    ],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Phlebothrombosis commonly affects the vein of the upper extremities.' Phlebothrombosis typically involves the formation of thrombi in the deep veins, often in the lower extremities, rather than the upper extremities. Arterial thrombi are usually occlusive and can occur in various arteries, including cerebral arteries. Venous thrombi are more commonly associated with occlusion, and their shape may conform to the contours of the vessel. Phlebothrombosis is a term often used to describe thrombosis in superficial veins or veins closer to the surface.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "Which of the following is not true about the characteristics of postmortem clots?",
    "options": [
      "There is always a point of attachment to the vessel wall",
      "It is gelatinous with a supernatant that resembles chicken fat",
      "It forms a cast of the blood vessel that it is found",
      "Do not have lines of Zhan",
      "Do not have a propagation tail"
    ],
    "answer": ["There is always a point of attachment to the vessel wall"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'There is always a point of attachment to the vessel wall.' Postmortem clots do not always have a point of attachment to the vessel wall. Unlike ante-mortem clots, postmortem clots can form within the vascular system after death and may not be attached to the vessel wall. Other characteristics of postmortem clots include their gelatinous nature, absence of lines of Zhan (a feature of ante-mortem clots), and lack of a propagation tail.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "Which is the commonest type of embolism",
    "options": [
      "Air embolism",
      "Amiotic fluid embolism",
      "Fat embolism",
      "Caisson disease",
      "Thromboembolism"
    ],
    "answer": ["Thromboembolism"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Thromboembolism.' Thromboembolism refers to the obstruction of blood vessels by a blood clot (thrombus) that has detached from its site of formation and traveled through the bloodstream. It is the most common type of embolism and can lead to serious consequences, such as pulmonary embolism when the clot lodges in the pulmonary arteries. Thromboembolism can occur in various blood vessels, causing ischemia or infarction in the affected organs or tissues.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "One of these statement is false in hypertrophy",
    "options": [
      "phosphoinositide 3-kinase pathway is said to be important in physiological hypertrophy",
      "There is increase in the number of cells and increase in the size of the organ or tissue",
      "Signaling G-protein coupled receptor is important in the pathogenesis",
      "Can be seen in cardiac and some type of smooth muscles",
      "There is increase in the number of myofilament"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "There is increase in the number of cells and increase in the size of the organ or tissue"
    ],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'There is an increase in the number of cells and increase in the size of the organ or tissue.' Hypertrophy involves an increase in the size of cells or tissues without a significant increase in the number of cells. It is a compensatory response to increased workload or demand. The other statements are correct: the phosphoinositide 3-kinase pathway is involved in physiological hypertrophy, hypertrophy can be seen in cardiac and some types of smooth muscles, and there is an increase in the number of myofilaments within the hypertrophied cells.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "The following mechanisms are seen in atrophy except",
    "options": [
      "There is increse autophagy",
      "Activation of ubiquitin-proteosome pathway",
      "Cell death by apoptotic mechanism",
      "Activation of phosphoinositide 3-kinase pathway",
      "Deficiency of nutrients"
    ],
    "answer": ["Activation of phosphoinositide 3-kinase pathway"],
    "explanation": "Atrophy is characterized by a decrease in the size and/or number of cells or tissues. The activation of phosphoinositide 3-kinase pathway is not typically associated with atrophy; instead, it may be involved in hypertrophy. The other mechanisms mentioned, such as increased autophagy, activation of the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway, cell death by apoptotic mechanism, and deficiency of nutrients, are known to contribute to atrophy.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "Which of the following features is not seen in necrosis?",
    "options": [
      "Karyolysis",
      "karyorrhexis",
      "pyknosis",
      "Chromatin condensation",
      "Inflammatory cell infiltrate"
    ],
    "answer": ["Chromatin condensation"],
    "explanation": "Chromatin condensation is a characteristic feature of apoptosis, not necrosis. In necrosis, the nucleus undergoes changes such as karyolysis (dissolution of the nucleus), karyorrhexis (fragmentation of the nucleus), and pyknosis (shrinkage of the nucleus). Additionally, necrosis is often associated with inflammatory cell infiltrate, which is not a prominent feature of apoptosis.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "A rapid host response that serves to deliver mediators of host defence to the site of an injurious agent do so in which one of the following chronological orders",
    "options": [
      "Transient vasoconstriction, stasis of blood flow, increase vascular permeability, Vasodilation",
      "Vasodilation, increase vascular permeability, stasis of blood flow, margination and rolling, adhesion and transmigration, chemostasis and activation",
      "Transient vasoconstriction, Increase permeability, Vasodilation, Stasis of Blood flow",
      "Neutrophil accumulation, vasodilation,increased permeability, stasis of blood flow",
      "Transient vasoconstriction, vasodilation, stasis of blood flow, endothelial gap formation in venules"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Vasodilation, increase vascular permeability, stasis of blood flow, margination and rolling, adhesion and transmigration, chemostasis and activation"
    ],
    "explanation": "Acute inflamation occurs in this other 'Vasodilation >> increased vascular permeability >> stasis of blood flow >> margination and rolling >> adhesion and transmigration >> chemostasis and activation' This sequence represents the events in Acute inflammation. Acute inflamation is a rapid host response to injurious agent that serves to deliver the mediators of host defence to site of injury. Vasodilation allows increased blood flow, increased vascular permeability leads to the leakage of plasma proteins and cells, stasis of blood flow aids in cell accumulation, margination and rolling bring white blood cells to the vessel wall, adhesion and transmigration allow the cells to move to the site of injury, and chemostasis and activation contribute to the immune response and inflammation.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "Leucocyte induced cellular killing in acute inflammation is mediated by",
    "options": [
      "Neutrophils",
      "Eosinophils",
      "Macrophages",
      "T-cells",
      "Monocyte"
    ],
    "answer": ["Neutrophils"],
    "explanation": "In acute inflammation, the primary mediators of leucocyte-induced cellular killing are neutrophils. Neutrophils are the first responders to sites of infection or injury, and they play a crucial role in phagocytosis and the release of various antimicrobial substances to eliminate the injurious agent. Their rapid recruitment to the site of inflammation is a key aspect of the acute inflammatory response.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "The delivery of leukocytes to the site of an infectious agent is key in its elimination.If this reaction occurs as a rapid host response with subsequent phagocytosis and elimination of the injurious agent; The leukocyte that mediates this killing is",
    "options": [
      "Eosinophils",
      "Mast cells",
      "Neutrophils",
      "Basophils",
      "Platelets"
    ],
    "answer": ["Neutrophils"],
    "explanation": "The rapid host response involving phagocytosis and elimination of an infectious agent is a characteristic feature of acute inflammation. Neutrophils are the primary leukocytes responsible for this process. They are quickly recruited to the site of infection or injury and are efficient phagocytes that play a central role in the early stages of the inflammatory response.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "Which of the following is correct with regards to the chemical mediators of inflammation",
    "options": [
      "Histamine is a plasma-derived mediator",
      "Serotonin is a AA metabolite",
      "Lipoxin is a vasoactive amine",
      "Complement protein are cell-derived mediators",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above"],
    "explanation": "Histamine is not a plasma-derived mediator. It is released from mast cells and basophils. Serotonin is not an AA (amino acid) metabolite; it is derived from tryptophan. Lipoxin is not a vasoactive amine; it is a specialized pro-resolving mediator derived from arachidonic acid. Complement proteins are not cell-derived mediators; they are plasma proteins that become activated during inflammation.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "The following factors are may cause the release of histamine with the exception of",
    "options": [
      "Heat",
      "Anaphylatoxins",
      "Attachments of antibodies to mast cells",
      "Bradykinins"
    ],
    "answer": ["Bradykinins"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Bradykinins.' While heat, anaphylatoxins, and attachment of antibodies to mast cells can induce the release of histamine, bradykinins do not directly cause histamine release. Bradykinins are a separate group of inflammatory mediators that can contribute to vasodilation, increased vascular permeability, and pain sensation in inflammation.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "One of the following is incorrect about chronic inflammation",
    "options": [
      "Neutrophils may be present",
      "Associated with tissue destruction",
      "Caseous necrosis may be seen tuberculous granuloma",
      "The most important cells are lymphocytes and macrophages",
      "Not a sequel of an acute inflammatory process"
    ],
    "answer": ["Not a sequel of an acute inflammatory process"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Not a sequel of an acute inflammatory process.' Chronic inflammation is often a sequel or consequence of persistent or repeated acute inflammatory processes. Neutrophils may be present initially, but chronic inflammation is characterized by the prolonged presence of mononuclear cells, including lymphocytes and macrophages. Chronic inflammation is associated with tissue destruction and repair.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "Chronic inflammation is characterized by the following except",
    "options": [
      "Tissue destruction",
      "Fibrosis",
      "Prolonged duration",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above"],
    "explanation": "Chronic inflammation is indeed characterized by tissue destruction, fibrosis (scar formation), and prolonged duration. Therefore, none of the provided options is incorrect. Chronic inflammation reflects an ongoing immune response to persistent stimuli, and it often involves a complex interplay of immune cells, inflammatory mediators, and tissue remodeling processes.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "Which of the following is not part of the chemokines family",
    "options": ["C-X-C", "C-C", "C3A", "C", "CX3C"],
    "answer": ["C3A"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'C3A.' Chemokines are a family of small proteins that induce chemotaxis, guiding the migration of cells. The options provided represent different classes of chemokines. However, C3A is not a chemokine; it refers to complement component 3a, which is a component of the complement system, not a chemokine involved in cell migration.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "An athlete sprained his left ankle joint during a training session.He complained of pain and swelling of the left ankle joint with associated inability to walk unaided. Which one of the following is responsible for the pain",
    "options": ["Bradykinin", "Fibrin", "TNF", "IL-1", "None of the above"],
    "answer": ["Bradykinin"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Bradykinin.' In the context of an acute injury, such as a sprained ankle, bradykinin is released as part of the inflammatory response. Bradykinin is a potent mediator that induces pain by sensitizing nerve endings. It also increases vascular permeability, contributing to the swelling observed in the affected joint. The pain and swelling are characteristic features of the acute inflammatory process.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "The extravasation of protein rich fluid",
    "options": [
      "Transuadate",
      "Albumin",
      "Exudate",
      "Natural killer cell",
      "Transudate exudation"
    ],
    "answer": ["Exudate"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Exudate.' Exudate refers to the extravasation of protein-rich fluid from the bloodstream into the interstitial tissue. It contains a higher concentration of proteins, cells, and debris compared to transudate. Exudate formation is a characteristic response to inflammation and is associated with increased vascular permeability, allowing proteins and cells to exit the blood vessels and enter the affected tissue.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "question": "Regarding chronic granulomatous inflammation, which is the most correct answer",
    "options": [
      "It is defined by presence of fibrosis",
      "It is defined by presence of giant cells",
      "It is always proceeded by inflammation",
      "It is defined by presence of epithelioid macrophages"
    ],
    "answer": ["It is defined by presence of epithelioid macrophages"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'It is defined by the presence of epithelioid macrophages.' Chronic granulomatous inflammation is characterized by the formation of granulomas, which consist of aggregates of epithelioid macrophages. These macrophages are transformed into an epithelioid appearance and, along with other immune cells, form a distinctive structure in response to persistent stimuli, often in the setting of infections or immune-mediated disorders.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "question": "Leukocyte extravasation occurs in the following order",
    "options": [
      "Adhesion, margination, rolling, transmigration, chemotaxis",
      "Margination,rolling, adhesion, transmigration,chemotaxis",
      "Transmigration, adhesion, margination, rolling chemotaxis",
      "Margination, adhesion, chemotaxis, rolling,transmigration"
    ],
    "answer": ["Margination,rolling, adhesion, transmigration,chemotaxis"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Margination, rolling, adhesion, transmigration, chemotaxis.' This sequence represents the ordered steps involved in leukocyte extravasation from the bloodstream to the site of inflammation. Margination involves the movement of leukocytes toward the vessel wall, rolling is the initial interaction with the endothelium, adhesion occurs through specific adhesion molecules, transmigration involves crossing the endothelial barrier, and chemotaxis guides the cells toward the inflammatory stimulus.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "question": "Granuloma",
    "options": [
      "It is a focus of acute inflammation",
      "Giant cell are absent",
      "Schistosomiasis is a non-granulomatous disease",
      "Consist of aggregates of epitheloid macrophages",
      "Macrophages are transformed into endothelium-like cells"
    ],
    "answer": ["Consist of aggregates of epitheloid macrophages"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Consists of aggregates of epithelioid macrophages.' A granuloma is a specific type of chronic inflammatory response characterized by the presence of clusters of epithelioid macrophages. These macrophages are surrounded by other immune cells, and the structure is often seen in response to persistent irritants or antigens. Giant cells may also be present in granulomas.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "question": "Which one of the following pair is correct",
    "options": ["Calor-swelling", "Rubor-redness", "Dolor-heat", "Tumour-pain"],
    "answer": ["Rubor-redness"],
    "explanation": "The correct pair is 'Rubor-redness.' These terms are part of the classic signs of inflammation described by Celsus. Rubor refers to redness, and it is caused by increased blood flow to the affected area. Therefore, redness (rubor) is a characteristic feature of the inflammatory response. Other characteristic  features of inflammation include Calor-heat, Tumor-swelling, Dolor-pain",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "question": "Leukocyte adhesion deficiency 1 is as a result of",
    "options": [
      "Histamine is a potent vasoconstrictor",
      "Transudate is a neutrophil rich extravascular fluid",
      "Immediate transient response usually lasting for 15-30 mins",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above"],
    "explanation": " Leukocyte adhesion deficiency 1 (LAD-1) is a genetic disorder characterized by a defect in the adhesion of leukocytes to the endothelium. It results in impaired immune cell recruitment to sites of infection or inflammation. The options provided do not correctly describe LAD-1; therefore, the answer is 'None of the above.'",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "question": "Effector cells of Type IV hypersensitivity reaction are",
    "options": [
      "TH1 CD4+T cells",
      "TH2 CD4+ T cells",
      "CD 15+ cells",
      "B cells",
      "CD45 lymphocytes"
    ],
    "answer": ["TH1 CD4+T cells"],
    "explanation": "In Type IV (Cell mediated or Delayed-type hypersensitivity reaction) there is <b>proliferation of antigen-specific CD4+ memory T cells</b>, with <b>secretion of IL-2 and other cytokines</b>, which in turn <b>recruit and simulated phagocytic macrophages</b>. It may also involve <b>cytotoxic CD8+ T lymphocyte killing of specific target cell</b>. \n\bExamples \n\b\b1. Tuberculin reaction \n\b\b2. Contact dermatitis \n\b\b3. Tumor cell killing \n\b\b4. viraly infected cell killing \n\b\b5. Mantous reaction \n\b\b6. Contact hypersensitivity(sensitivity)\n\b\b7. Rheumatoid arthritis \n\b\b8. Multiple sclerosis \n\b\b9. Type 1 diabetes mellitus \n\b\b10. Hashimoto thyroiditis",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "question": "Which of these diseases is mediated by Type II hypersensivity reaction",
    "options": [
      "Congenital adrenal hyperplasia",
      "Erythroblastosis fetalis",
      "Rheumatic fever",
      "Urticaria",
      "Tuberculosis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Erythroblastosis fetalis"],
    "explanation": "In <b>Type 2</b> hypersensitivity (<b>antibody-mediated</b> or <b>cytotoxic</b>) Antibodies react with antigens that are intrinsic components of cell membrane or other structures, such as basement membranes, resulting in <b>direct damage complement-mediated increased susceptibility to phagocytosis</b>, or <b>antibody-dependent cell-mediated cytotoxicity,</b> also may be caused by <b>inactivation of cell-surface receptors by antireceptor antibodies</b> \n\bExamples \n\b\b1. Warm Antibody autoimmune hemolytic anemia \n\b\b2. Hemolytic disease of the newborn\n\b\b3. Goodpasture syndrome\n\b\b4. Graves disease \n\b\b5. Transfusion reactions \n\b\b6. Acute rheumatic fever \n\b\b7. Insulin-resistant diabetes \n\b\b8. Autoimmune hemolytic anemia, agranulocytosis, and thrombocytopenia.\n\b<b>Immune system component involved</b>\n\b\b1. IGM \n\b\b2. IgG \n\b\b3. Complement",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "question": "The following are true of type I hypersensitivity reaction",
    "options": [
      "Mediated by IgE antibodies",
      "Early phase response is mediated by leukotrienes",
      "Graves disease is a prototype",
      "Marked vasoconstriction in late phase",
      "Occurs in non-sensitized individuals"
    ],
    "answer": ["Mediated by IgE antibodies"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Mediated by IgE antibodies.' Type I hypersensitivity reactions are immediate hypersensitivity reactions mediated by IgE antibodies. In response to an allergen, IgE antibodies on mast cells and basophils bind to the allergen, triggering the release of histamine and other mediators. This rapid release of mediators leads to the characteristic symptoms of immediate hypersensitivity, such as itching, swelling, and bronchoconstriction.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "question": "Which of these diseases is mediated by Type III hypersensitivity reaction",
    "options": [
      "Graves disease",
      "Autoimmune agranuloctosis",
      "Systemic lupus erythromatosis",
      "Erythroblastosis fetalis",
      "Contact dermatitis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Systemic lupus erythromatosis"],
    "explanation": "In Type III hypersensitivity reaction (Immune complex/complex-mediated) insoluble complement-bound aggregates of antigen-antibody complexes are deposited in vessel wall or on serosal surface or other extravascular sites. Neutrophils are chemotactically attracted and release lysosomal enzymes, prostaglandins kinins and free radicals, resulting in tissue damage\n\b Examples \n\b\b1. Serum sickness \n\b\b2. Arthus reaction\n\b\b3. Polyarteritis nodosa \n\b\b4. Systemic lupus erythromatosus\n\b\b5. Immune complex-mediated glomerular disease \n\b\b6. Intrinsic allergic alveolitis \n NOTE <b>Graves disease, Autoimmune agranulocytosis </b> and <b>Erythroblastosis fetalis</b> are Examples of Type II hypersensitivity (antibody-mediated or Cytotoxic) reactions  while <b>Contact dermatitis</b> is a Type IV (Cell-mediated or delayed-type hypersensitivity) reaction",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "question": "Which of the following is a type II hypersensitivity reaction",
    "options": [
      "Serum sickness",
      "Arthus reaction",
      "Atropy",
      "Antibody dependent cell mediated cytotoxicity",
      "Direct cell cytotoxicity"
    ],
    "answer": ["Antibody dependent cell mediated cytotoxicity"],
    "explanation": "In <b>Type 2</b> hypersensitivity (<b>antibody-mediated</b> or <b>cytotoxic</b>) Antibodies react with antigens that are intrinsic components of cell membrane or other structures, such as basement membranes, resulting in <b>direct damage complement-mediated increased susceptibility to phagocytosis</b>(Direct cell cytotoxicity), or <b>antibody-dependent cell-mediated cytotoxicity,</b> also may be caused by <b>inactivation of cell-surface receptors by antireceptor antibodies</b> \n\bExamples \n\b\b1. Warm Antibody autoimmune hemolytic anemia \n\b\b2. Hemolytic disease of the newborn\n\b\b3. Goodpasture syndrome\n\b\b4. Graves disease \n\b\b5. Transfusion reactions \n\b\b6. Acute rheumatic fever \n\b\b7. Insulin-resistant diabetes \n\b\b8. Autoimmune hemolytic anemia, agranulocytosis, and thrombocytopenia.\n\b<b>Immune system component involved</b>\n\b\b1. IGM \n\b\b2. IgG \n\b\b3. Complement",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "question": "Which of these is not a feature of acute serum sickness",
    "options": [
      "Acute necrotizing vasulitis",
      "Glomerulonephritis",
      "Serositis",
      "Arthritis",
      "Sinusitis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Sinusitis"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Sinusitis.' Acute serum sickness is an immune complex-mediated hypersensitivity reaction that occurs in response to the administration of certain drugs or foreign proteins. The typical features include acute necrotizing vasculitis, glomerulonephritis, serositis (inflammation of serous membranes), and arthritis. Sinusitis is not a characteristic feature of acute serum sickness.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "question": "Which of these statements is not true of systemic lupus erythematosus",
    "options": [
      "Children are rarely affected",
      "May be associated with prolonged use of procainamide",
      "Low levels of antinuclear antibodies in serum",
      "Patients may present with nephrotic syndrome",
      "LE test is positive"
    ],
    "answer": ["Low levels of antinuclear antibodies in serum"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Low levels of antinuclear antibodies in serum.' Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is characterized by the production of autoantibodies, including antinuclear antibodies (ANA). In SLE, the levels of ANA are typically elevated, and the LE (lupus erythematosus) test is positive. Children can be affected by SLE, and the use of procainamide is a known trigger for drug-induced lupus.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "question": "Which of these is not a morphologic features of amyloidosis",
    "options": [
      "Macroglossia",
      "Vegetations in the heart valves",
      "Lardaceous spleen",
      "Glomerulonephritis",
      "Sub endocardial amyloid deposits"
    ],
    "answer": ["Vegetations in the heart valves"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Vegetations in the heart valves.' Amyloidosis is a condition characterized by the extracellular deposition of abnormal protein fibrils. While amyloid deposits can be found in various organs and tissues, including the heart, the formation of vegetations in the heart valves is not a typical morphologic feature of amyloidosis.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "question": "HIV entry into T cells does not require",
    "options": ["CCR5", "Gp45", "CXCR4", "Gp41", "Gp 120"],
    "answer": ["Gp45"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Gp45.' HIV (Human Immunodeficiency Virus) entry into T cells involves interactions between viral glycoproteins and host cell receptors. Gp120 on the viral envelope binds to CD4 receptors on T cells, and this interaction is followed by binding to a co-receptor (CXCR4 or CCR5). Gp45 is not a known glycoprotein involved in the entry process.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "question": "Which of these is an AIDS defining neoplasm",
    "options": [
      "Astrocytoma",
      "Rhabdosarcoma",
      "Nephroblastoma",
      "Kaposi sarcoma",
      "Ewing sarcoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Kaposi sarcoma"],
    "explanation": "Patients with AIDS have a high incidence of certain tumors, especially \n1.  Kaposi sarcoma (KS),\n2. Non-Hodgkin B-cell lymphoma, \n3. Cervical cancer in women, and \n4. Anal cancer in men.\n\n A common feature of these tumors is that they are all believed to be caused by oncogenic DNA viruses, that is,\n1.   kaposi sarcoma herpesvirus (Kaposi sarcoma),\n2. EBV (B-cell lymphoma), \n3. Human papillomavirus (cervical and anal carcinoma)\n\n Even in healthy people, any of these viruses may establish latent infections that are kept in check by a competent immune system. \n\n   The increased risk of malignancy in AIDS patients exists mainly due to\n1. Failure to contain the infections \n2.  Reactivation of the viruses, \n3. Decreased immunity against the tumors.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "question": "The following factor does not encourage progression to AIDS",
    "options": [
      "IL-10",
      "TNF-α",
      "INF-γ",
      "Herpes simplex infection",
      "Tuberculosis"
    ],
    "answer": ["IL-10"],
    "explanation": "Completion of life cycle of Hiv in a latently infected cell occurs only after cell activation by antigen or cytokines like TNF, IL-1, IL-2, IL-6, IFN-γ, GM-CSF    ",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "question": "Which of these is not involved in the actiopathogenesis of SLE",
    "options": [
      "Tuberculosis",
      "Ultraviolet radiation",
      "Hyper estrogenic state",
      "Procainamide",
      "Penincillamine"
    ],
    "answer": ["Tuberculosis"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Tuberculosis.' Tuberculosis is not typically associated with the pathogenesis of Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE). SLE is an autoimmune disease with a complex etiology involving genetic, environmental, and hormonal factors. Factors like ultraviolet radiation, hormonal changes, and certain medications like procainamide and penicillamine have been implicated in the development or exacerbation of SLE.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "question": "Which of these is properly matched",
    "options": [
      "Amyloid light protein (AL)-- Multiple myeloma",
      "Amyloid Associated protein (AA)--Alzheimer",
      "Aβ amyloid protein-- haemodialysis",
      "Transthyetin --- secondary amyloidosis",
      "β2 microglobulin --- heredo-familial amyloidosis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Amyloid light protein (AL)-- Multiple myeloma"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Amyloid light protein (AL)-- Multiple myeloma.' Amyloid light chain (AL) amyloidosis is associated with multiple myeloma. In this disorder, plasma cells produce excess light chains that can form amyloid fibrils. Other forms of amyloidosis involve different proteins and are associated with various conditions, such as Alzheimer's disease, hemodialysis (Aβ amyloid protein), and hereditary conditions (β2 microglobulin).",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "question": "Which of these is involved in central tolerance",
    "options": [
      "Molecular mimicry",
      "Anergy",
      "Foxp3 gene",
      "Autoimmune regulator gene",
      "NOD-2 gene"
    ],
    "answer": ["Autoimmune regulator gene"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Autoimmune regulator gene.' Central tolerance refers to the mechanisms by which the immune system eliminates or inactivates self-reactive lymphocytes during their development. The autoimmune regulator (AIRE) gene plays a crucial role in central tolerance by promoting the expression of tissue-specific antigens in the thymus, allowing the elimination of autoreactive T cells.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "question": "Which of these is a systemic autoimmune disease",
    "options": [
      "Diabetes mellitus",
      "Myasthenia gravis",
      "Graves disease",
      "Hashimoto thyroiditis",
      "Systemic lupus erythematosus"
    ],
    "answer": ["Systemic lupus erythematosus"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Systemic lupus erythematosus.' SLE is a systemic autoimmune disease characterized by the production of autoantibodies and immune complex deposition. It can affect multiple organs and tissues, leading to a wide range of clinical manifestations. Other options, such as diabetes mellitus, myasthenia gravis, Graves disease, and Hashimoto thyroiditis, are autoimmune diseases but may not manifest as extensively as SLE.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "question": "The followings are Autosomal Dominant Disorders except",
    "options": [
      "Neurofibromatosis",
      "Polycystic kidney disease",
      "Achondroplasia",
      "Glycogen storage diseases",
      "Familial polyposis coli"
    ],
    "answer": ["Glycogen storage diseases"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Glycogen storage diseases.' Autosomal Dominant Disorders are typically characterized by the presence of a single mutated copy of a gene that leads to the manifestation of the disorder. Glycogen storage diseases, on the other hand, are a group of disorders involving the malfunction of enzymes in glycogen metabolism. They are usually inherited in an autosomal recessive manner.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of Sex linked Disorders",
    "options": [
      "Familial polyposis coli",
      "Spinal muscle atrophy",
      "Huntington disease",
      "Cystic fibrosis",
      "Duchenne muscle dystrophy"
    ],
    "answer": ["Duchenne muscle dystrophy"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Duchenne muscle dystrophy.' Sex-linked disorders, also known as X-linked disorders, are caused by mutations in genes located on the X chromosome. Duchenne muscle dystrophy is an X-linked recessive disorder caused by a mutation in the DMD gene located on the X chromosome. The other options are associated with autosomal inheritance.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "question": "Autosomal Recessive Disorders include the following conditions except",
    "options": [
      "Wilsons disease",
      "Sickle cell anaemia",
      "Glucose-6- phosphate dehydrogenase",
      "Thalassemias",
      "Alkaptonuria"
    ],
    "answer": ["Glucose-6- phosphate dehydrogenase"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase.' Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency is inherited in an X-linked recessive manner, not autosomal recessive. The other options, Wilson's disease, sickle cell anemia, thalassemias, and alkaptonuria, are examples of autosomal recessive disorders. Examples of Sex linked disorders are Hemophilia, Glucose 6- phosphate dehydrogenase deficinecy and Y- linked hypogonadism",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "question": "Marfan syndrome is characterized by the following except",
    "options": [
      "Subluxation of the lens",
      "Dolichocephalic",
      "Mutation of FBN I gene",
      "Mitral valve prolapse",
      "Gauchers cells"
    ],
    "answer": ["Gauchers cells"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Gaucher's cells.' Marfan syndrome is a connective tissue disorder caused by a mutation in the FBN1 gene, leading to abnormalities in fibrillin-1. Clinical features include subluxation of the lens, dolichocephalic (long and narrow) body habitus, mutation of FBN1 gene, and mitral valve prolapse. Gaucher's cells are associated with Gaucher disease, a lysosomal storage disorder, not Marfan syndrome.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "question": "Familial Hypercholesterolaemia is characterized by one of the following presentation namely",
    "options": [
      "Glycogen accumulation",
      "Sphingomyelin accumulation",
      "Glycolipid accumulation",
      "Premature atherosclerosis",
      "Gauchers cells"
    ],
    "answer": ["Premature atherosclerosis"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Glycolipid accumulation.' Familial Hypercholesterolemia is a genetic disorder characterized by elevated levels of low-density lipoprotein (LDL) cholesterol in the blood. This leads to the deposition of cholesterol in the arteries, resulting in premature atherosclerosis. The accumulation of glycolipids is not a characteristic feature of Familial Hypercholesterolemia.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "question": "Down syndrome is characterized by one of the following",
    "options": [
      "More than 90% of the patient are mosaic",
      "Robertsonian Translocation may be involved",
      "Trisomy 18",
      "47,XX,+18 karyotype",
      "Not predisposed to leukemia"
    ],
    "answer": ["Robertsonian Translocation may be involved"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Robertsonian Translocation may be involved.' Down syndrome, or trisomy 21, is typically characterized by the presence of an extra copy of chromosome 21. However, in some cases, Down syndrome can result from Robertsonian Translocation, where a portion of chromosome 21 is translocated to another chromosome. This accounts for a small percentage of Down syndrome cases.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "question": "Klinefelter syndrome is associated with the following disorder",
    "options": [
      "45,X/47,XXX karyotypes",
      "Gynaecomastia may be present",
      "Hypertrophic testicular tubules",
      "Streak ovaries",
      "Atrophic leydig cells"
    ],
    "answer": ["Gynaecomastia may be present"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Gynaecomastia may be present.' Klinefelter syndrome is a genetic disorder characterized by the presence of an extra X chromosome in males (47,XXY). Gynaecomastia, or the development of breast tissue in males, is a common feature of Klinefelter syndrome. Other features may include hypogonadism, tall stature, and infertility.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "question": "Turners syndrome is characterized by one of the following",
    "options": [
      "Leydig cell hypertrophy",
      "Streak ovaries",
      "Menorrhagia",
      "Simians crease",
      "Eunochoid body habitus"
    ],
    "answer": ["Streak ovaries"],
    "explanation": "Turner Syndrome: Results from complete or partial monosomy of the x chromosome and is characterized by hypogonadism in females. It is the most common sex chromosome abnormality in females.\nTurner's syndrome is characterized by,\n1. Oedema at infancy on the extremities and the neck due to lymph  stasis,\n2. neck webbing short stature,\n2. hypothyroidism,\n3. broad chest and widely spaced nipple streak  ovaries, \n5. amenorrhoea, \n6. coartation of the aorta with features of congenital heart dx.  \n7. Delayed or lack of develop secondary sexual maturity.\n\n Fetal ovaries develop normally in  embryogenesis but the absence of the second x chromosomes lead to accelerated loss of oocytes  which is complete before 2 to 3 years which means that menopause may occur before menarche  and the ovaries are reduced to streak ovaries (atrophic fibrous strand without oval or follicles)",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "question": "Florescent In-situ Hybridization is characterized by the following except",
    "options": [
      "DNA probes that can recognize specific sequences in a chromosome",
      "For identifying chromosomal changes",
      "Performed on prenatal samples",
      "For detecting aneuploidy",
      "Specificity of result is very low"
    ],
    "answer": ["Specificity of result is very low"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Specificity of result is very low.' Fluorescent In-situ Hybridization (FISH) is a molecular technique used to detect and locate the presence or absence of specific DNA sequences on chromosomes. FISH is known for its high specificity and is widely used for identifying chromosomal changes, detecting aneuploidy, and performing prenatal testing. The specificity of FISH results is generally high.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "question": "The following are molecular diagnosis and their application in genetic disorders",
    "options": [
      "Southern blot -- Complex genetic translocation",
      "FISH -- Gene amplification",
      "Southern blot -- RNA analysis mainly",
      "Polymerase chain reaction -- population study and screening for genetic disorders",
      "Northern blot -- DNA studies"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Polymerase chain reaction -- population study and screening for genetic disorders"
    ],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Northern blot -- DNA studies.' Northern blot is a molecular technique used to study gene expression by detecting RNA in a sample. It is particularly used for RNA analysis. However, the option 'Northern blot -- DNA studies' is incorrect, as Northern blot is primarily used for RNA, not DNA. The other options correctly match the techniques with their applications.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "question": "A 17 year old patient presented at the outpatient clinic with complaints of severe retrosternal pain of one day duration. He was properly examined by a physician, after proper evaluation and investigations he was diagnosed to have Familial Hypercholesterolaemia, which of the following pathological feature is in keeping with the above named diagnosis",
    "options": [
      "Myocardial infarction may occur early in life",
      "Scoliosis",
      "Long extremities",
      "Sphingomyelin accumulation",
      "Joint hypermobility",
      "Onchronosis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Myocardial infarction may occur early in life"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Myocardial infarction may occur early in life.' Familial Hypercholesterolemia is associated with elevated levels of low-density lipoprotein (LDL) cholesterol, leading to the premature development of atherosclerosis. Individuals with this condition are at an increased risk of myocardial infarction at an early age. The other options are not typically associated with Familial Hypercholesterolemia.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "question": "Pseudohermaphroditism is characterised by the following features",
    "options": [
      "Male Pseudohermaphroditism may be associated with testicular feminization",
      "In female pseudohermaphrodite there is complete androgen insensitivity",
      "In male pseudohermaphrodite, the genetic sex is XX-chromosome",
      "Female pseudohermaphrodite possess a XY chromosomes",
      "Presence of ovotestis is usually associated with pseudohermaphroditism"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Male Pseudohermaphroditism may be associated with testicular feminization"
    ],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Male Pseudohermaphroditism may be associated with testicular feminization.' Pseudohermaphroditism refers to conditions where the external genitalia do not match the chromosomal or gonadal sex. Male Pseudohermaphroditism may be associated with testicular feminization (Androgen Insensitivity Syndrome), where individuals with a 46,XY karyotype have defective androgen receptors, leading to incomplete masculinization of external genitalia.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "question": "Mendelian Disorders are characterized by the following except",
    "options": [
      "Mutation (permanent change) in a single gene with large phenotypic effect",
      "Most of these disorders are recessive",
      "Only few cases are familial",
      "Majority of cases are familial",
      "Sickle cell anaemia is an example of Mendelian disorder"
    ],
    "answer": ["Only few cases are familial"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Only few cases are familial.' Mendelian disorders are typically characterized by mutations in single genes with a large phenotypic effect. These disorders can be either dominant or recessive, and they often run in families. Sickle cell anemia, for example, is a Mendelian disorder that follows an autosomal recessive inheritance pattern. The statement 'Only few cases are familial' is incorrect, as many Mendelian disorders have a familial tendency.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "question": "Autosomal recessive disorders are characterized by the followings except",
    "options": [
      "Complete penetrance is common",
      "Early onset of life",
      "They are among the least common group of mendelian disorders",
      "Sibling have 25% chance of having the trait in each life birth",
      "Many of the mutated genes encode enzymes"
    ],
    "answer": ["They are among the least common group of mendelian disorders"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'They are among the least common group of Mendelian disorders.' Autosomal recessive disorders are characterized by traits that manifest in individuals who inherit two copies of the mutated gene (homozygous recessive). These disorders are relatively common, and their frequency is influenced by consanguinity. The statement 'They are among the least common group of Mendelian disorders' is incorrect, as autosomal recessive disorders are not uncommon.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "question": "Down syndrome may be characterized by the following except",
    "options": [
      "Mental retardation",
      "Congenital heart defect",
      "Umbilical hernia",
      "Epicanthic folds",
      "Not compactable with life"
    ],
    "answer": ["Not compactable with life"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Not compatible with life.' Down syndrome (Trisomy 21) is characterized by the presence of an extra chromosome 21. Individuals with Down syndrome can lead fulfilling lives, and the condition is compatible with life. The other options, including mental retardation, congenital heart defects, umbilical hernia, and epicanthic folds, are commonly associated features of Down syndrome.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "question": "Neurosyphilis",
    "options": [
      "Manifests as firm raised red non tender lesions on the head",
      "Tabes dorsalis is a generalized brain parenchymal disease",
      "General paresis is paralysis due to spinal cord involvement",
      "The presence of antibodies to spirochetes in CSF in the absence of neurologic symptoms is indicative",
      "Is treated with short course antibiotic therapy"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "The presence of antibodies to spirochetes in CSF in the absence of neurologic symptoms is indicative"
    ],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'The presence of antibodies to spirochetes in CSF in the absence of neurologic symptoms is indicative.' Neurosyphilis is a late manifestation of syphilis that can involve the central nervous system. The presence of specific antibodies to Treponema pallidum in the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) even in the absence of neurologic symptoms is indicative of neurosyphilis. The other options describe various features and manifestations of neurosyphilis.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "question": "Which of the following is a transforming Virus",
    "options": [
      "Ebstein Barr Virus",
      "Human Papilloma Virus",
      "Hepatitis C virus",
      "All of the above",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["All of the above"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'All of the above.' Transforming viruses are capable of inducing uncontrolled cell growth and transformation, leading to the development of tumors. Epstein-Barr Virus (EBV), Human Papillomavirus (HPV), and Hepatitis C virus (HCV) are examples of transforming viruses. These viruses are associated with the development of certain cancers. The option 'All of the above' is the correct answer, as all three viruses mentioned have transforming capabilities.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "question": "Primary Tuberculosis",
    "options": [
      "Develops in previously exposed, unsensitized persons",
      "Does not progress",
      "The source of organism is endogenous",
      "Presents as an apical cavitary lesion",
      "May present as an upper lower lobe consolidation"
    ],
    "answer": ["May present as an upper lower lobe consolidation"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'May present as an upper lower lobe consolidation.' Primary tuberculosis is the initial infection with Mycobacterium tuberculosis. It typically occurs in individuals who are previously exposed but unsensitized. Primary tuberculosis may present with various manifestations, and one of the possible presentations is as an upper lower lobe consolidation. The other options describe characteristics of primary tuberculosis, including its development in previously exposed unsensitized individuals.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "question": "The following are true of pathogenesis of TB except",
    "options": [
      "TH1 response orchestrates the formation of granulomas and caseous necrosis",
      "Macrophages become batericidal when activated by IFN-γ",
      "Activated macrophages secrete TNF, to recruit more monocytes",
      "Hypersensitivity is evidence of immunity",
      "Loss of hypersensitivity can occur in the face of persisting immunity"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Loss of hypersensitivity can occur in the face of persisting immunity"
    ],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Loss of hypersensitivity can occur in the face of persisting immunity.' In the pathogenesis of tuberculosis (TB), hypersensitivity reactions are indicative of cell-mediated immunity. However, in some cases, loss of hypersensitivity can occur despite persisting immunity, and this phenomenon is known as anergy. Anergy may be observed in individuals with advanced or severe forms of TB. The other options describe various aspects of the immune response and pathogenesis of TB.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "question": "Which of these are correctly matched",
    "options": [
      "River blindness -- fresh water snails",
      "Treponema pallidum--Sleeping sickness",
      "Trypanosomes--hepar lobatum",
      "Onchocercoma--Simulium black fly",
      "River blindness--hepar lobatum"
    ],
    "answer": ["Onchocercoma--Simulium black fly"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Onchocercoma--Simulium black fly.' \n Onchocercoma is associated with Onchocerca volvulus, a parasitic worm causing river blindness. The black fly of the genus Simulium serves as the vector for Onchocerca volvulus. The other options are incorrect matches. Treponema pallidum is the bacterium causing syphilis, not sleeping sickness (which is caused by Trypanosoma species). The remaining options are also incorrect matches.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "question": "Protozoa",
    "options": [
      "Are multicellular organisms",
      "Cause filariasis",
      "May be intracellular",
      "None of the above is correct",
      "All of the above are correct"
    ],
    "answer": ["May be intracellular"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'May be intracellular.' Protozoa are single-celled eukaryotic organisms, and they can be either intracellular or extracellular. Some protozoa are capable of living inside host cells, causing intracellular infections. The other options are incorrect. Protozoa do not cause filariasis, and they are not multicellular organisms. Therefore, the correct answer is 'May be intracellular.'",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "question": "Regarding the mantoux test, the following can cause a false positive reaction Except",
    "options": [
      "Immunosuppression",
      "Hodgkins Lymphoma",
      "Sarcoidosis",
      "Malnutrition",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above"],
    "explanation": "Infection  with M. tuberculosis leads to the development of delayed hypersensitivity to M. tuberculosis antigens, detectable by the tuberculin (Mantoux) skin test, 2 to 4 weeks after infection. \n\nA positive tuberculin test result signifies T cell–mediated immunity to mycobacterial antigens, but does not differentiate between infection and disease. \n\nFalse-negative reactions may occur in the setting of certain \n1. viral infections, \n2. sarcoidosis, \n3. malnutrition, \n4. Hodgkin lymphoma, \n5. immunosuppression, and \n6. (notably) overwhelming active tuberculous disease. \n\nFalse-positive reactions may result from \n1. infection by atypical mycobacteria or \n2. prior vaccination with BCG (Bacillus Calmette-Guerin).",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "question": "Regarding the mantoux test. The following can cause a false positive reaction",
    "options": [
      "Infection with atypical mycobacteria",
      "Certain viral infections",
      "Overwhelming active tuberculous disease",
      "Immunosuppression",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Infection with atypical mycobacteria"],
    "explanation": "Infection  with M. tuberculosis leads to the development of delayed hypersensitivity to M. tuberculosis antigens, detectable by the tuberculin (Mantoux) skin test, 2 to 4 weeks after infection. \n\nA positive tuberculin test result signifies T cell–mediated immunity to mycobacterial antigens, but does not differentiate between infection and disease. \n\nFalse-negative reactions may occur in the setting of certain \n1. viral infections, \n2. sarcoidosis, \n3. malnutrition, \n4. Hodgkin lymphoma, \n5. immunosuppression, and \n6. (notably) overwhelming active tuberculous disease. \n\nFalse-positive reactions may result from \n1. infection by atypical mycobacteria or \n2. prior vaccination with BCG (Bacillus Calmette-Guerin).",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "question": "The following are true of Primary tuberculosis except",
    "options": [
      "Primary TB may be in the gastrointestinal tract",
      "Primary tuberculosis occurs solely in the lungs",
      "About 5% of newly infected people develop clinically significant disease",
      "The elderly and profoundly immunosuppressed may lose memory cells and develop primary tuberculosis more than once",
      "The source of organism is endogenous"
    ],
    "answer": ["Primary tuberculosis occurs solely in the lungs"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Primary tuberculosis occurs solely in the lungs.' Primary tuberculosis can affect various organs, and it is not limited to the lungs. While pulmonary involvement is common, primary TB can also occur in extrapulmonary sites, including the gastrointestinal tract. Therefore, the statement 'Primary tuberculosis occurs solely in the lungs' is incorrect.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "question": "Concerning syphilis",
    "options": [
      "latent phase may last 5 years or more",
      "Cardiovascular syphilis is a manifestation of seconday disease",
      "Syphilitic aortitis, accounts for more than 80% of cases of secondary syphilis",
      "In Neurosyphilis CSF parameters are normal",
      "None of the above is true"
    ],
    "answer": ["latent phase may last 5 years or more"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Latent phase may last 5 years or more.' Syphilis has three stages: primary, secondary, and latent. The latent phase is characterized by the absence of symptoms, and it may last for several years. The statement 'Latent phase may last 5 years or more' is correct. The other options include accurate statements about syphilis manifestations, such as cardiovascular syphilis and CSF parameters in neurosyphilis.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "question": "Plasmodium vivax and P.ovale cause",
    "options": [
      "Low level parasitemia and severe anaemia",
      "High level parasitemia and Mild anaemia",
      "Splenic rupture and Nephrotic syndrome",
      "Repeated relapses of malaria and cerebral malaria",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above"],
    "explanation": " Plasmodium vivax and P. ovale are malaria parasites that cause relapsing malaria. They do not typically cause the mentioned complications, such as severe anemia, splenic rupture, nephrotic syndrome, or cerebral malaria. The relapses are due to the parasites' ability to form hypnozoites in the liver, leading to recurrent episodes. Therefore, the statement 'None of the above' is correct.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "question": "Concerning Treponema pallidum. The following are true except",
    "options": [
      "Spread is by sexual contact",
      "Transplacental transmission is usual",
      "Active disease in pregnancy results in congenital syphilis",
      "It is a gram negative cocci",
      "Cannot be cultured for diagnosis"
    ],
    "answer": ["It is a gram negative cocci"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'It is a gram-negative cocci.' Treponema pallidum is a spirochete bacterium, not a gram-negative cocci. It is responsible for causing syphilis, and it has a distinctive spiral shape. The other options are true statements about Treponema pallidum, including its transmission, transplacental transmission causing congenital syphilis, and the difficulty of culturing the bacterium for diagnosis.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "question": "Which of theses are not correctly matched",
    "options": [
      "Syphilis -- Treponema pallidum",
      "Hansen\"s disease -- Mycobacterium leprae",
      "Kala-azar ---- Trypanosoma spp",
      "Black fever--LD bodies",
      "Lepra cell -- Globi"
    ],
    "answer": ["Kala-azar ---- Trypanosoma spp"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Black fever--LD bodies.' 'Black fever' is commonly known as visceral leishmaniasis, and it is caused by Leishmania species, not LD bodies. LD bodies are associated with the diagnosis of leprosy (Hansen's disease). Therefore, the option 'Black fever--LD bodies' is not correctly matched, making it the correct answer.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "question": "The infective form of Malaria parasite is the",
    "options": ["Oocyst", "Merozoite", "Sporozoite", "Schizoint", "Gametocyte"],
    "answer": ["Sporozoite"],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 'Sporozoite.' The sporozoite is the infective form of the malaria parasite. It is the stage transmitted to humans through the bite of an infected Anopheles mosquito. Once in the bloodstream, sporozoites travel to the liver and infect hepatocytes, initiating the malaria infection cycle. The other options represent different stages in the malaria life cycle.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "question": "Which of the following is true of Malaria",
    "options": [
      "Hyperendemic/ high endemic zones: there is persistent year-round transmission",
      "Hyperendemic/ highly endemic zones: The spleen rate is >75% and parasite rate >75%",
      "Stable of holoendemic zones: The spleen and parasite rates are between 50 and 74% ",
      "Stable or holoendemic zones: Malarial transmission is seasonal",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above"],
    "explanation": "1. In Stable or holoendemic zones:  there is persistent year-round transmission. The spleen rate is >75% and parasite rate > 75%   \n2. In Hyperendemic/ highly endemic zones: the spleen and parasite rates are between 50 and 74%. Malarial transmission is seasonal; mainly during the raining season which decreases during the dry season. Nigeria is a hyperendemic zone for malaria with pockets of holoendemic and mesoendemic zones \n3. Mesoendemic zone: the spleen and parasite rates range between 11 and 49 % with a short transmission period an average annual rainfall of about 2months. \n4. Hypoendemic zone: the spleen and parasite rates are 10%. The transmission of malaria is known to occur but may be absent",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "Med 160 1st test",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  }
]
